University of Connecticut, Fire Department Records 2012.0085
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
University of Connecticut, Fire Department Records
1950-1972
2012.0085
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
6.75 Linear feet
The collection contains incident logs, telephone logs and lost and found records created by the University of Connecticut Fire Department between 1950 and 1971 and one log from the Police Department.
University of Connecticut
Arrangement
The collection is divided into four series: Series I: Incident Logs includes descriptions of each incident next to a code for that call. Weather is always noted. Fire emergency incidents are written in red. The incident logs also include maintenance notes about the fire engines. Series II: Telephone call logs document calls to the fire department. Red hash marks next to each fire emergency call; many of these volumes have loose bindings. Series III: Lost and Found Logs includes information documenting when the item was received and if identified, notes about who later claimed the item(s). Series IV: Police log contains one volume.
Scope and Content Note
The collection containes three types of log books maintained by the University Fire Department from 1950 through 1969. These log books document the day to day activities of the department. For example, the incident logs include descriptions of the weather, engine maintainence, and locales to which they were called. Telephone logs include fire calls as well as alarm calls, office locking procedures and evidence of the implementation of automated communications. The lost and found volumes provide evidence of the range of property found on campus during the years covered. Most of the logs have 500 pages, although there are a few whose pages have not been completely filled, one with 300 pages and one with 150 pages.
History
In April 1881, the Connecticut General Assembly established the Storrs Agricultural School after accepting a gift of 170 acres of land, several frame buildings, and money from Charles and Augustus Storrs. The School opened on 28 September 1881, with twelve students in the first class. Before the turn of the century there were two name changes ( Storrs Agricultural College 1893, Connecticut Agricultural College 1899). In 1933, two years after the institution celebrated its fiftieth anniversary, it became Connecticut State College, a name more in keeping with its steady advances and broadened mission. Six years later, in 1939, the General Assembly designated the institution the University of Connecticut, an acknowledgment of the institution's developing importance to the State in graduate and professional education, research and public service.
As the University grew, so did its needs for an on-campus fire department. In the early years of the University, help for fire-related emergencies came from the surrounding towns. During the period of this collection of record log books, the University of Connecticut’s Fire Department was its own entity, answering calls for campus-related emergencies and concerns.
Specific information about the Department can be found on their website.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Provenance and Acquisition
The collection was transferred by the UConn Fire Department on 29 June 2012.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
University of Connecticut; University of Connecticut; Archives (institutions); University of Connecticut.
- Series I: Incident Logs (34 volumes), 1950-1972
  - 1950 January 5 – 1950 October 31 (Box 1)
  - 1950 October 31 – 1951 July 26 (Box 1)
  - 1951 July 26 – 1952 April 30 (Box 1)
  - 1952 April 30 – 1953 March 2 (Box 1)
  - 1953 March 3 – 1954 January 4 (Box 1)
  - 1954 January 5 – 1954 October 31 (Box 1)
  - 1954 November 1– 1955 August 9 (Box 1)
  - 1955 August 9 – 1956 May 16 (Box 1)
  - 1956 May 16 – 1957 March 1 (Box 1)
  - 1957 March 1– 1957 December 22 (Box 1)
  - 1957 December 22 – 1958 March 19 (Box 1)
  - 1958 March 19 – 1958 December 30 (Box 1)
  - 1958 December 30 – 1959 October 7 (Box 2)
  - 1959 October 7 – 1960 July 3 (Box 2)
  - 1960 July 3 – 1961 April 8
  - 1961 April 8 – 1962 January 19 (Box 2)
  - 1962 January 19 – 1962 October 21 (Box 2)
  - 1962 October 21 – 1963 July 14 (Box 2)
  - 1963 July 15 – 1963 December 21 (Box 2)
  - 1963 December 21 – 1964 September 11 (Box 2)
  - 1964 September 12 – 1965 May 30 (Box 2)
  - 1965 March 24 - 1966 April 29 (Box 6)
  - 1965 May 30 – 1966 February 11 (Box 2)
  - 1966 February 11 – 1966 October 23 (Box 2)
  - 1966 October 24 - 1967 June 21 (Box 5)
  - 1967 June 22 - 1967 December 9 (Box 5)
  - 1967 December 9 - 1968 May 9 (Box 5)
  - 1968 May 10 - 1969 January 30 (Box 5)
  - 1969 January 30 - October 15 (Box 5)
  - 1969 October 15 - 1970 June 12 (Box 5)
  - 1970 June 12 - 1971 January 30 (Box 5)
  - 1971 January 31 - September 27 (Box 5)
  - 1971 September 27 - 1972 May 1 (Box 5)
  - 1972 May 1 - December 31 (Box 6)
- Series II: Telephone Logs (18 vols.), 1950-1969
  - 1950 May 5 – 1951 June 14 (Box 3)
  - 1951 June 14 – 1952 May 23 (Box 3)
  - 1952 May 23 –1953 July 21 (Box 3)
  - 1953 July 21– 1954 October 14 (Box 3)
  - 1954 October 14 – 1955 December 13 (Box 3)
  - 1955 December 12 – 1957 January 15 (Box 3)
  - 1957 January 1 – 1958 February 17 (Box 3)
  - 1958 February 17 - 1959 January 29 (Box 3)
  - 1959 January 29 – 1959 September 23 (Box 3)
  - 1959 September 23 – 1960 June 17 (Box 3)
  - 1960 June 17 - 1961 April 3 (Box 4)
  - 1961 April 3 – 1962 February 14 (Box 4)
  - 1962 February 15 – 1963 January 31 (Box 4)
  - 1963 January 31 – 1964 February 5 (Box 4)
  - 1964 February 6 – 1965 March 24 (Box 4)
  - 1966 April 29 – 1967 April 5 (Box 4)
  - 1967 June 13 – 1968 August 6 (Box 4)
  - 1968 August 6 – 1969 September 28 (Box 4)
- Series III: Lost and Found Logs (2 vols.), 1955-1968
  - 1955 October 24 – 1962 October 3 (Box 4)
  - 1962 October 3 – 1968 March 19 (Box 4)
- Series IV: Police Log (1 vol.), 1964-1965
  - 1964 March 30 - 1965 August 31 (Box 5)